marcelcutts

full-stack engineer

contact

Address withheld on public CV

Number withheld on public CV

me@marcelcutts.com marcelcutts.com

languages

English fluency German basic

programming

Python, JavaScript Ruby, Elm, Swift C#, Java, C++ SQL, PLSQL, noSQL CSS3 & HTML5

favourite tech

Microservices, React / Flux WebSockets Functional things Immersive UX

methodologies

TDD, BDD Scrum/Kanban UX, UCD

synopsis

Full stack engineer with consultancy and business experience.

I am an exceptional generalist, having experienced a swath of different technologies and project types. I take an immense joy in building great software that positively impacts the world and am an outspoken advocate for good software and team practices.

When not behind a computer, I climb rocks, dive oceans, fight people, run and play guitar talentlessly.

employment

2014-201_ **Six to Start**

Full Stack Engineer

For the last year and a half, I have been working to rapidly scale Six to Start's flagship fitness app, "Zombies, Run!", to its current 2.3 million users.

Day to day, I architect and implement scalable back-end and front-end systems to serve a monumental amount of runners world wide, generate new developer platforms and procedures, build internal systems that help others produce content, and create fantastical marketing sites for new ventures.

2011-2014 **Tessella**

Oxford, United Kingdom

London, United Kingdom

Software Engineer

During my time at Tessella, I had opportunities to work on an exceptional variety of development and consultancy projects across domains. This has ranged from designing and implementing large scale n-tier applications to analysing and advising on processes in the consumer industry.

Internally, I championed new technologies and methodologies, as well as leading small teams and mentoring developers.

2010 **Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron**

Hamburg, Germany

Particle Physicist

My efforts at the DESY institute focused on combining knowledge of physics and programming ability to contribute to an upcoming particle accelerator, the International Linear Collider. As part of my role, I regularly presented to international audiences to promote updates from the department and attended numerous specialised lectures.

2009–2010 **De La Rue**

London, United Kingdom

Research and Development Scientist

De La Rue allowed me contribute to upcoming securityproducts across many areas of science. Throughout I developed my own ideas, mostly within the realm of software, but also within materials science and optics.

Within the broader team, I participated in designing, prototyping and refining oncoming products, including work in holographics, polymer development, photonic crystals and printed electronics.

education

2007–2011 **Physics** with industrial experience

Thesis on the superstate of b-meson oscillations.

University of Bristol